本作品由Norm Team傾情奉獻
感謝原作提供資源.僅供學習交流.嚴禁用於商業行為
請自覺於下載後24小時內刪除!如果喜歡本片,請購買正版!
更多精彩 盡在www.NormTeam.com
壓制:鬼谷子 字幕:鬼谷子
Compression:GV-Sir Subtitles:GV-Sir
新基督山伯爵
1814年 法國皇帝拿破侖·波拿巴 被流放到愛爾巴島 靠近意大利海岸
逮捕他的英國人擔心有人會來營救他
任何靠近的人都會被殺害 ...
...不論是多麼無辜的人
白癡
Idiots.
把上尉帶到暗礁上 直到我們允許靠岸為止
Take the captain beyond the reef till we get permission to bring him ashore.
我認為你們應該暫時把我放下
For a moment I thought you were abandoning me.
費爾南德·蒙德哥不會讓他的朋友面臨自毀的危險
Fernand Mondego does not abandon his friends in the face of stupid,suicidal danger.
不管怎樣 作為這次航行的莫雷爾的正式代表 愛德蒙
However,as Monsieur Morell's official representative on this voyage,Edmond,
我必須正式地告訴你 你越過了二副的職責
I must officially tell you you have overstepped your bounds as second mate.
應該說 我超過了我自己
Officially.There.I've covered myself.
如果不讓他看醫生 他會死的 明白嗎?
If we don't get him to a doctor,he will die.Do you understand?
我當然明白 不要期望我保持冷靜
Of course I understand.Just don't expect me to do this sober.
好
Right.
英國騎兵
English dragoons.
喂!
Hello!
唐太斯 不要
Dantes,don't.
- 你不認為我們要小心一點? - 我們必須要跟人接觸
- A little careless,don't you think? - We have to talk to someone.
我知道 但...
Well,I know,but...
我們是法國水手
We're French sailors!
- 我們需要醫生! - 過來 過來
- We seek medical attention! - Come on.Come on.
- 我們是友好的 - 過來
- We come in peace. - Come on.
我們是說沒有危險
We mean no harm!
埃德蒙!
Edmond!
過來 爬上來!
Come on!Climb!
當心!
Look out!
費爾南德!
Fernand!
太好了 終於擊中了
Good.You finally hit something.
格瑞布爾上尉
Lieutenant Graypool.
如果你們渴望得到這些可憐傢伙的血
If your thirst for gore demands the death of these poor fools,
那麼用盡一切辦法殺他們
then by all means shoot them.
動腦筋 他們不是我的代理商
But do so with the knowledge they are no agents of mine.
現在為你們自己辯解或者被殺
Now explain yourselves or be shot.
先生 我叫埃德蒙·唐太斯
Sir,I am Edmond Dantes,
是法老號船上的二副 我們在回馬塞的途中
second mate of the merchant ship Pharaon,on our way home to Marseilles.
這是船主的代理人 費爾南德·蒙德哥先生
This is the shipowner's representative,Monsieur Fernand Mondego,
蒙德哥伯爵之子
son of the Count Mondego.
我們的船長得了腦膜炎 所以我們停在這裏尋求幫助
Our captain has contracted brain fever,so we put in here for help.
如果他真的昏迷 就對我的刀尖沒有感覺 不是嗎?
If his coma is genuine,he won't feel my knife point,will he?
就劃一刀
Only a scratch.
埃德蒙
Edmond!
- 格瑞布爾上尉! - 我們是誠心誠意來的
- Lieutenant Graypool! - We came to you in good faith!
- 那是為病人好 - 無疑是病了
- That's for my wounded men. - And wounded pride,no doubt.
一個多事的夜
It has been an eventful evening.
如果我不殺這些騎兵 你門可能馬上屍骨無存的躺在岸邊了
If I hadn't have shot those dragoons,you might by lying in pieces on the beach right now.
- 我幾乎讓我們被殺 - 是的
- I almost got us killed. - Yes,you did.
還好 我們活下來了
Yet...we survive.
保佑你 弗爾南多
King's to you,Mondego.
做你的朋友總是很危險
Being your friend is always an adventure.
- 是的 不是這樣嗎?
Yes,it is,isn't it?
冒險家沒有朋友是很可憐的 嗯?
It's a pity adventurers can't always be friends though,huh?
什麼?
What?
不會總像這樣 不是嗎?
Well,it won't always be like this,will it?
- 你在說什麼? - 沒什麼 喝酒
- What are you talking about? - Nothing.Drink up.
我們在喝拿破侖·波拿巴的酒
We're drinking Napoleon Bonaparte's wine.
我想你們會發現1806的上好的葡萄酒
I think you'll find the 1806 The finer vintage.
只要你仍然活著 唐太斯先生 不知...
As long as you're still awake,Monsieur Dantes,I wonder...
我是否可以跟你們說句話
if I might have a word with you.
我很驚奇 下象棋的意義是什麼?
I'm curious.What's the significance of the chess piece?
它只是我自孩子以來一直做的事
It's just something we've done since childhood.
不管什麼時候我們勝利了 就是統治的時候
Whenever one of us has had a victory,king of the moment.
- 統治的時候? - 對
- King of the moment? - Yes.
生活中 我們不是統治者就是被統治
In life,we're all either kings or pawns.
我會努力挽救你們船長的生命 唐太斯
I'm moved by your effort to save your captain's life,Dantes.
他是我的船長...朋友 閣下
He is my captain...and my friend,Your Majesty.
忠誠的朋友的確很可貴
Loyal friends are rare indeed.
事實上 我有件事想說
In fact,it is upon such a matter I wish to speak.
我給在馬賽的朋友寫了封傷感的信
I have written a rather sentimental letter to an old comrade in Marseilles.
裏面有我的情況 我不想讓英軍看到
It's a side of me I prefer the British not see.
因為他們喜歡打開我的郵件
Since they have a habit of opening my mail,
不知你是否可以幫我送這封信
I wonder if you would deliver it for me.
我 我不能
Oh,I-I don't...
只是從一個老士兵手裏轉到另一個的手裏
It's just a letter from one old soldier to another.
我保證 絕對安全
It's totally innocent,I assure you.
但更重要的是 醫藥費就不用付了
But more important,it is the price I demand for the use of my physician.
那好
Then I agree.
很好
Good.
你把這封信送到諾瓦蒂埃先生那裏
You are to deliver the letter to Monsieur Clarion.
- 記住了那個名字嗎? - 諾瓦蒂埃先生 我怎麼找到他?
- Can you remember that name? - Monsieur Clarion.How will I find him?
他會找你
Oh,he will find you.
我不希望這封信被任何其他的人知道
Now,I do not wish this letter's existence to be known to anyone else.
甚至連你的好友 明白嗎?
Not even your boon companion back there.Do you understand?
我是個守信的人 閣下
I'm a man of my word,Your Majesty.
好 我相信你是個守信的人
Yes,I,uh...I believe you are.
他想幹什麼?
What did he want?
從法國傳來消息 就這些
Oh,um,news from France.That's all.
你們的船長已經死了半個小時了
Time you were on your way.Your captain has been dead for half an hour.
真的嗎?
Are you sure?
當你和我在田野裏散步的時候 年輕的唐太斯
When you have walked as many battlefields as I,young Dantes,
你可以感覺 他已經死了
you can feel death.
統治和被統治
Kings and pawns,Marchand.
帝王...和傻子
Emperors...and fools.
改變方向
Come about!
開快點
Drive faster.
騰格拉爾 發生了什麼事?
Danglars,what's happened?
萊克勒船長死了 先生
Captain Reynaud is dead,sir,
愛德蒙·唐太斯不聽我的命令
and Edmond Dantes disobeyed my orders.
到我的辦公室來 騰格拉爾
Come to my office and report,Danglars.
- 還有你 愛德蒙. - 是我嗎 莫雷爾先生
- And you,Edmond. - Will you be needing me,Monsieur Morell?
去
Go.
美塞苔絲
Mercedes.
- 他在哪?愛德蒙在哪? - 見到你真高興
- Where is he?Where is Edmond? - How lovely to see you too.
恐怕你看錯過了
You just missed him,I'm afraid.
可能要等一會兒 我想他現在有麻煩
Could be a while.I think he's in trouble.
他說他會到岩石邊找我們 走吧
He said he'd meet us by the rock.Come on.
我告訴過唐太斯不要上岸
I told Dantes not to go ashore.
有這回事嗎?
Is this true?
我承擔所有的責任
I accept all responsibility.
你應該承擔 全是他的主意 先生
As well you should.It was all his idea,monsieur.
應該是你的主意吧
It should have been your idea.
停泊在厄爾巴島 沒有救活船長的生命
Puttin' into Elba didn't save the captain's life,monsieur.
- 我要保護貨物 - 你在保護自己...
- I was protectin' the merchandise. - You were protecting yourself...
在船上躲起來
by hiding behind your rank and staying aboard.
愛德蒙·唐太斯我命令你為法老號的新船長
Edmond Dantes,I am making you the new captain of the Pharaon.
你要降我的級嗎?
You presume to demote me?
沒有降級
There is no demotion.
你還是唐太斯船長手下的大副
You will remain first mate under Captain Dantes.
當然 除非你不想幹了
Unless,of course,you choose to seek another berth.
現在我在想一定有位女士...
Now I imagine there's a certain young lady...
很想聽到這個消息
who will want to hear this news.
- 謝謝你
Thank you.
莫雷爾先生?
Monsieur Morell?
- 我知道有一艘船#剛從厄兒巴島回來先生 - 是的
- I understand you had a ship just returned from Elba,monsieur. - Yes.
船上有人碰巧下船嗎?
Did anyone aboard get ashore there by any chance?
他們都下了 但他們現在不在這裏
They did,but they're not here at the moment.
謝謝你 先生
Thank you,monsieur.
- 可以問誰叫他們嗎? - 諾瓦蒂埃
- May I say who has called upon them? - Clarion.
名叫諾瓦蒂埃
The name is Clarion.
- 跟我做愛 - 你曾經放棄過嗎?
- Make love to me. - Will you ever give up?
- 他不會知道 - 我知道
- He doesn't have to know. - I'd know.
那麼可以嗎
So would I.
- 它是我們的小秘密 - 我不相信秘密
- It'd be our little secret. - I don't believe in secrets.
你以為愛德蒙沒有秘密嗎?他有 問他
You think Edmond doesn't have secrets?He does.Ask him.
- 我知道你想什麼 費爾南多 - 你知道?
- I know what you want,Fernand. - You do?
還記得我還是孩子的時候 愛德蒙在生日上得了一個口哨
Remember when we were kids and Edmond got that whistle for his birthday
你得了一個小馬嗎?
and you got a pony?
你們都樂瘋了 愛德蒙比你得到小馬更高興
You were so mad Edmond was happier with his whistle than you were with your pony.
我不想成為你的下一個口哨
I'm not going to be your next whistle.
你認為愛德蒙多久能娶到妻子?
How long do you think it's going to be before he can afford a wife?
兩年 兩年 夠了
Two years.Two years.That's all.
那時他可以是船長 我們就可以結婚
Then he gets his captain's papers,and we can marry.
兩年 我等不了兩年
Two years.I couldn't wait two years for anything,
特別是像你這樣的新娘
particularly a bride like you.
嗨
Hey!
他在那 - 嗨!
- There he is. - Hey!
美塞苔絲
- Whoo! - Mercedes!
我很想你
I missed you so.
現在不想了
The missing is over now.
- 有麻煩嗎? - 不 我是船長了 過來
- Are you in trouble? - No.I'm captain.Come on.
莫雷爾先生給我那個頭銜
Monsieur Morell gave me the Pharaon.
愛德蒙!
Edmond!
祝福我
King's to me.
你總是很幸運 愛德蒙
Yours is a life truly blessed,Edmond.
過來
Come on.
- 你仍然是個那麼優秀 - 我知道
- You're still the best man. - I know.
走啊!
Come on!
不要想了 你會變成禿子的
Stop that.You'll go bald.
你對我有秘密嗎?
Do you keep secrets from me?
秘密?沒有
Secrets?No.
為什麼?
Why?
問什麼我都告訴你
Ask me anything and I'll tell you.
我們不用再等兩年了
We don't have to wait two years anymore.
- 當我能買戒指時 我們就結婚- - - 我不要戒指 不要
- As soon as I can afford the ring,we'll wed... - I don't need a ring.I don't.
這就是我的戒指
This will be my ring.
無論發生什麼事
And no matter what happens,
你都會見它在我的手指上
you will never see it off my finger.
永遠
Ever.
嗨 我年輕的先生
Hello,my fine young gentleman.
跟我喝酒吧?
Care to join me?
告訴我 蒙德哥
So tell me,Mondego,
你們是怎麼成為朋友的...
how did you ever become friends...
和那個正直的傢伙 愛德蒙·唐太斯?
with that righteous little ponce,Edmond Dantes?
他要做我的朋友
He claims to be my friend,
他竟敢對我保守秘密
yet he has the audacity to keep secrets from me.
什麼秘密?
What secrets?
為法老號的新船長乾杯
To the new captain of the Pharaon.
都是您的功勞 爸爸
All I am I owe to you,Father.
希望幸福的時刻不要結束...
May this happy moment be but the dawn...
願你們有長久快樂的幸福生活
of a long and wonderful life for you both.
- 誰是愛德蒙·唐太斯? - 是我
- Which of you is Edmond Dantes? - I am.
愛德蒙唐太斯受地方官之命你被捕了
Edmond Dantes,you are under arrest by order of the magistrate of Marseilles.
- 被捕? - 有什麼罪?
- Arrest? - On what charges?
罪名要保密 帶走他
That information is privileged.Take him.
我想解釋一下!我想解釋一下
I demand an explanation.I demand an explanation!
今晚我會回來的 不要擔心 爸爸 這是誤會
I'll be back tonight.Don't worry,Father.This is a mistake.
天哪
Mon Dieu.
我想說 唐太斯 你看起來不像叛國賊
Well,I must say,Dantes,you don't have the look of a traitor.
叛國賊?
Traitor?
現在 聽我說唐太斯 你的命運就決定於此
Now,attend me well,Dantes,for your life may depend on it.
你在厄爾巴島時 跟拿破侖有過私人的接觸嗎
Did you have any personal contact with Napoleon when you were on Elba?
厄爾巴島 是的 有過 我們有過
Elba,yes,I did.Well,we did.
我和蒙德哥伯爵之子 費爾南多 幾乎是同時
I was with the Count Mondego's son,Fernand,almost the entire time.
- 你認識費爾南多? - 最近才認識
- Do you know Fernand? - He's a recent acquaintance,yes.
你們去找他 他可以證明
Oh,there you are.He'll vouch for me.
不用懷疑 但你說"幾乎是同時
No doubt,but you said,"almost the entire time."
除了拿破侖叫我給他 在馬賽的朋友送一封私人信件
Except for when Napoleon asked me to deliver a personal letter to a friend in Marseilles.
那麼唐太斯 它就跟叛國有關...
Well,Dantes,it is for accepting that treasonous correspondence...
你是被你自己的大副揭露的 一位叫騰格拉爾先生
that you have been denounced by your own first mate,a Monsieur Danglars.
- 什麼? - 信送了嗎?
- What? - Did you deliver the letter?
沒有 長官 有人會找我
No,sir,someone was supposed to find me.
它還在我的口袋裏 這裏
It's...It's still in my jacket.Here.
- 你看過嗎? - 沒有 長官
- Have you read this? - No,sir,I can't read.
唐太斯 這是給拿破侖同夥的一封信
Well,Dantes,this is a letter to one of Napoleon's agents.
它說了厄爾巴島英國海軍 出巡的時間和地點
It gives the times and the locations of the British beach patrols on Elba.
長官 我發誓 我不知道
Sir,I swear on my mother's grave,I had no idea.
他保證過內容沒有危害
He swore its contents were innocent.
不 現在是你 你是無辜的
No,it's you that's innocent.
愚蠢無知
Foolish and innocent.
這些對你很不利
I believe these are the worst charges that could be leveled against you.
幸運的是 我中途截了這封信 沒有危險了
Fortunately,as I've intercepted this document,there's no harm done.
上帝知道你會倖存在世界上 愛德蒙·唐太斯
God knows how you're going to survive in this world,Edmond Dantes.
但你不是叛國賊
But you are no traitor.
你可以走了
You may go.
謝謝你 長官
Thank you,sir.
等等 拿破侖有告訴過你 誰回來取那封信
Wait,uh,did Napoleon tell you who's supposed to pick up the letter?
諾瓦蒂埃.先生
Monsieur Clarion.
什麼名字?
What name did you say?
諾瓦蒂埃.先生
Monsieur Clarion.
你向其他人提過這個名字嗎?
Have you mentioned this name to anyone else?
蒙德哥先生或其他人?
Monsieur Mondego or anyone?
沒有 長官 事實上蒙德哥先生什麼都不知道
No,sir,in fact,Monsieur Mondego knows nothing of this letter.
這封信很危險
This is very dangerous information.
一個人不能知道的太多
One can never be too careful in times like this.
- 你說是嗎? - 是 長官
- Don't you think? - Yes,sir.
我給了你壓力
I've given you rather a stressful time.
我不知道道歉可不可以 我可以提供我的馬車
I wonder if,by way of an apology,I could offer you my carriage home.
就在這裏
It's just through here.
謝謝你
Thank you.
維爾福先生?維爾福先生?
Monsieur Villefort?Monsieur Villefort?
維爾福先生!
Monsieur Villefort!
你們把我帶到哪裏?
Where are you taking me?
這是個誤會
This is a mistake.
- 讓我回家 - 從現在開始 你的家在伊夫堡監獄
- I'm allowed to go home. - From now on,your home is the prison Chateau d'lf.
- 不不不
No!No!No!
嗨
Hey!
開槍
Shoot him now!
追上去!抓住他
Mount up!Get after him!
費爾南多!費爾南多!
Fernand!Fernand!
- 先生? - 沒事 他在這裏 費爾南多!
- Monsieur? - It's all right.He's right here.Fernand!
我因叛國罪被拘捕 我差點逃不出來
I've been arrested for treason.I barely managed to escape.
我在厄爾巴島時 拿破侖給了我一封信
When we were on Elba,Napoleon gave me a letter.
我沒有告訴你 是因為他叫我發過誓
I didn't tell you because he made me promise not to.
他說是給一個老朋友的
He said it was just some note to an old friend.
但那個雜種對我撒謊 他騙我
But the bastard lied to me!He lied.
那是他的一個同夥
It was to one of his agents.
被人發現 我不知道該怎麼辦
Somehow the authorities found out.I don't know what to do.
有憲兵在後面抓我
There's gendarmes on horseback right behind me.
好 我們必須想一想
All right.We just have to think.
我希望不會給你帶來危險
I hope I haven't compromised you.
我希望你父親能幫我
I was hoping your father could help me.
他在巴黎 病得很嚴重
He's in Paris.He's very ill.
- 憲兵離這有多遠? - 就幾分鐘
- How far back are the gendarmes? - Minutes.
- 需要錢嗎? - 是的 謝謝
- Do you need money? - Yes,thank you.
- 要手槍嗎 - 當然不要
- Do you have a pistol? - Of course not.
好
Good.
放下 費爾南多 我沒有時間玩這個
Stop it,Fernand.I don't have time for this.
我看見拿破侖給了你信
I saw Napoleon give you that letter.
是你?
It was you?
不是我 是騰格拉爾的主意
Well,it wasn't just me.It was Danglars's idea.
為什麼你開始不說
Why didn't you come to me first?
為什麼你要對我保密呢?我把你當作我的好朋友
Why did you keep it a secret from me?I thought you were my friend.
我告訴過你 我答應過他不食言 但他對我撒謊!
I told you I gave Napoleon my word.He lied to me!
我知道 愛德蒙我看了那封信
I know,Edmond.I read the letter.
你- - 你看了- - -
You...You read...
為什麼要這樣做?
Why are you doing this?
太複雜了
Oh,it's complicated.
Complicated.
不要傻了
Don't be ridiculous.
- 讓我走 - 我不能讓你走 愛德蒙
- Get out of my way. - I can't let you go,Edmond.
從窗戶逃離
Get away from the window.
我不會放了你!
Don't make me take off your hand!
為什麼?到底是為什麼?
Why?In God's name,why?
因為你是小職員的兒子
Because you're the son of a clerk!
我不想跟你一樣
And I'm not supposed to want to be you.
- 這裏 - 這裏
- In here! - In here!
- 抓 - 等等
- Get! - Wait.
- 拿著 拿著
Hold it.Hold it.
記住美好的日子
To remember better days.
走
Come on!
我告訴過你命運不會總像這樣 愛德蒙
I told you it wasn't always going to be this way,Edmond.
爸爸 他在哪裏??
Father!Where is he?
書房 他做了什麼?
The study.What's he done now?
現在 你聽我說 爸爸我是主要的地方官 是新政體的官員
Now,you listen to me,Father.I am the chief magistrate,an official of the new regime.
我不允許我父親 與叛國之事有何牽連
I cannot afford to have my own father mixed up in treasonous affairs!
你知道
You know...
叛逆就是個時期的問題
In the end,treason is a matter of dates.
當君主重新登位時我就是愛國者 你就是叛逆者
I shall be the patriot,and you the traitor,when the emperor returns.
住嘴 住嘴 你老糊塗了
Stop it.Stop it,you old ruin.
那些日子已經結束了 拿破侖 波拿巴不再是君主
Those days are over.Napoleon Bonaparte is no longer the emperor of anything.
如果你再繼續胡鬧 因為你的同情心...
If you continue to dabble in this lunacy,you run an excellent chance...
很可能被捕 毀了我們全家
of being arrested and ruining our entire family all because of your idiotic sympathies.
至少我有同情心
At least I have sympathies.
看在上帝的份上 父親 瓦倫蒂娜說的...
For God's sake,Father,all Valentina is saying...
我們整個家族的命運都會牽扯進去
is that as a family our fates are intertwined.
- 希望您能明白 - 明白
- Surely you can see that. - See?Ah!
我老糊塗了
I'm an old ruin.
我不明白我做了什麼 你們要原諒我
I don't see as well as I did.You will excuse me.
走
Move it.
Move.
歡迎 唐太斯先生
Welcome,Monsieur Dantes.
我叫阿蒙得 朵裏克 是伊夫堡的監管
I am Armand Dorleac,the warden of Chateau d'lf.
先生 我知道你一定聽說了這件事
Monsieur,I know you must hear this a great deal,
我保證我是無辜的
but I assure you I am innocent.
每個人都會那樣說 我知道 但我真的是無辜的
Everyone must say that,I know,but I truly am.
- 無辜 - 對
- Innocent. - Yes.
我知道 我真地知道
I know.I really do know.
- 你嘲笑我? - 不 我親愛的唐太斯
- You mock me? - No,my dear Dantes.
我很清楚地知道你是無辜的 你來這裏有別的原因嗎
I know perfectly well that you are innocent.Why else would you be here?
如果你真的犯了罪
If you were truly guilty,
法國有幾百囚犯 他們會把你藏起來的
there are a hundred prisons in France where they would lock you away,
但伊夫堡是個恥辱的地方
but Chateau d'lf is where they put the ones they're ashamed of.
我可以看看你的住址嗎?
Let's have a look at your quarters now,shall we?
"上帝會給我公平的
"God will give me justice."
人們總是盡力激發他們自己
People are always trying to motivate themselves.
或者把他們自己藏起來 但不久就會失去興趣或死去
Or they keep calendars,but soon they lose interest or they die.
- 有窗 - 只剩下一堵看不見的牆 我害怕
- There's a window. - All I'm left with is a rather unsightly wall,I'm afraid.
所以我想了另一個方法 幫助我們的囚犯打發時間
So I conceived of another way to help our prisoners keep track of time.
每年 在他們進獄的時候
Every year,on the anniversary of their imprisonment,
我們會傷害他們
we hurt them.
通常只是一頓簡單的鞭打
Usually just a simple beating really.
今天是你進獄的第一天 所以也一樣
Although,on their first day here,in your case,today,
我喜歡做一些怪事
I like to do something rather special.
如果你現在在想
And if you're thinking just now,
"為什麼是我 天啦?
"Why me,O God?"
- 答案是 上帝不會幫你 - 知道嗎?
- The answer is,God has nothing to do with it. - All right?
事實上 上帝不會在這個時候的法國出現
In fact,God is never in France this time of year.
上帝與所有事都有關 他無處不在 他看見了一切
God has everything to do with it.He's everywhere.He sees everything.
好吧
All right.
我們做個交易 好嗎?
Let's make a bargain,shall we?
你向上帝尋求幫助 他出現了我就停止打你
You ask God for help,and I'll stop the moment he shows up.
維爾福先生 你沒有聽說嗎?
Monsieur Villefort,have you not heard?
- 拿破侖從厄爾巴島逃走了 - 什麼?
- Napoleon has escaped from Elba! - What?
在離這的一百英里登陸 向巴黎進軍
Landed 100 miles from here.He marches on Paris!
裝好我的文件 叫那個白癡職員找到底帳
Pack all my files.And tell that idiot clerk to find the ledger!
我們來這裏是為了愛德蒙·唐太斯的事 長官
We are here to plead the case of Edmond Dantes,Magistrate.
不是現在 唐太斯?
Not now!Dantes?
我們沒有見過 長官 我是費爾南多·蒙德哥 蒙德哥伯爵的兒子
We have not met,monsieur.I am Fernand Mondego,the son of Count Mondego.
我發誓 愛德蒙·唐太斯是清白的
I am here to swear to Edmond Dantes's innocence.
這是他的船主莫雷爾先生 他的父親和他的未婚妻美塞苔絲
This is his employer,Monsieur Morell,his father,and his fiancee,Mercedes.
愛德蒙·唐太斯被指控犯了很嚴重的叛國罪
Edmond Dantes is charged with high treason.
- 你仍然相信他? - 我當然相信
- Yet you stand by him? - Of course I do.
如果我告訴你 唐太斯也被控告謀殺呢?
What if I was to tell you that Dantes is also charged with murder?
- 謀殺? - 愛德蒙不會做這種事
- Murder? - Edmond would never do such a thing.
唐太斯為拿破侖 給他的同黨帶信
Dantes carried a letter from Napoleon to one of his agents.
我們抓他時 他殺了我的一個人
When we tried to arrest him,he killed one of my men.
如果你瞭解他 長官 你就知道那是不可能的
No,if you knew him,monsieur,you would know that was not possible.
發發慈悲吧
Have mercy,please.
你有叛國的證據嗎?
You have proof of this treason?
那是政府的事
That is government business.
請告訴我他在哪裏?
Please.Please,just tell us where he is.
我不能 小姐 他是君主控制的人
I cannot,mademoiselle.He was handed over to the king's men.
我能夠理解你的痛苦
I can understand your pain at this betrayal.
但我勸你們忘掉愛德蒙·唐太斯
But my advice to all of you would be to forget Edmond Dantes,
特別是你
particularly you,mademoiselle.
接受你好朋友的安慰吧...
Take solace in the comfort of your good friend here...
也許痛苦過後就是幸福
and perhaps some good may yet come of this unhappy affair.
請你們原諒 我還有別的的事
Now,you will excuse me.I have to attend some other matters.
我兒子沒罪!
My son is no traitor!
我會盡力幫他的
I will try to reason with him.
- 讓費爾南多說說吧 他也許能幫忙 - 永遠不可能了
- Let's leave this to Fernand.He can plead the case. - It's impossible.Never.
我不會放棄
I will not give up on Edmond yet.
我不會忘記你的恩情
I will never forget your kindness.
我也不會放棄
And I shall never cease to give it.
不是我不喜歡犯罪的辯詞
Not that I don't appreciate the embroidery of the crimes,
還有謀殺嗎?
but still,murder?
真的很簡單
It's quite simple really.
當你向我檢舉唐太斯收了一封信時
When you reported Dantes's receiving the letter to me,
我不理解你為什麼要出賣他
I didn't quite understand why you were betraying him,
但現在見到他美麗的未婚妻後 我完全明白了
but now having seen his exquisite fiancee,I understand completely.
這麼好 有什麼指示嗎?
What prompts you to be so accommodating?
請坐 蒙德哥
Sit down,Mondego.
回來!
Come back!
回來
我犯了什麼罪?我犯了什麼罪?
What's my crime?What's my crime?
我是無辜
I'm innocent!
每年快樂 唐太斯
Happy anniversary,Dantes.
等明年
Until next year.
整整四年了 德利烏斯?
Has it really been four years,Delius?
或丹東?他叫什麼?
Or Danton?What is his name again?
請原諒我的闖入
Forgive my intrusion.
我在底下的監獄裏
But I was under the impression that I...
我一直在向上挖
I was digging toward the outer wall.
你懂英語嗎?
Parlez-vous anglais?
意大利語?
Italiano?
我是神父 法利亞 我在伊夫堡坐牢十一年了
I am Abbe Faria.I have been a prisoner in Chateau d'lf for 11 years.
花了五年的時間...
Five which have been spent...
挖這個地道
digging this tunnel.
一共有七萬二千五百一十九塊石頭...
There are 72,519 stones...
在我的牆上
in my walls.
我已數了無數遍了
I've counted them many times.
給他們取了名字嗎?
But have you named them yet?
噓 小聲點
Shh,shh.
曾經我跟你現在一樣
Once I was as you are now.
但我相信 一切都會過去的
But I promise,it will pass.
我相信 我相信
I promise,I promise.
現在 我可以站在你的肩膀上嗎?
Now,may I stand on your shoulders?
放我下來
Take me down.
請放我下來
Please,take me down now.Take me down.
我有十一年沒有見過陽光了 謝謝你
I have not seen the sky these 11 years.Thank you.
感謝上帝
Thank you,God.
沒有上帝 牧師
There is no talk of God in here,priest.
這些刻字是怎麼回事兒?
What about the...inscription?
已經褪色了 就像上帝在我心裏褪色一樣
It's faded,just as God has faded from my heart.
- 取而代之的是什麼? - 仇恨
- And what has replaced it? - Revenge.
拿著
Hold these.
跟著我
Follow me.
也許你的仇恨思想...
Perhaps your thoughts of revenge...
是上帝讓你活著的目的...
are serving God's purpose of keeping you alive...
這七年
these seven years.
- 什麼時候結束? - 逃跑
- To what end? - Escape.
我們到了
There we go.
剛才你提到了逃
You spoke of escape.
是啊
Yeah.
有兩種可能可以到外界
There are only two possibilities of reaching the outer wall...
一直到海上
and finally the sea.
我只選擇了錯路
I simply...I simply chose the wrong one.
現在 有我們兩個
Now,of course,with two of us,
我們可以向相反的方向挖
we could dig in the opposite direction.
我們一起 可能會挖八年
With both of us together,then,of course,we could possibly do it in,oh,eight years.
你有別的事要做嗎?
Oh,does something else demand your time?
或許是某個緊急的約會?
Some pressing appointment,perhaps?
你的幫助會有回報的
In return...for your help,
我給你無價之寶
I offer something priceless.
我的自由?
My freedom?
不 自由可以剝奪
No,freedom can be taken away,
你很清楚
as you well know.
我給你知識 我學過的所有知識
I offer knowledge,everything I have learned.
我會教你經濟學 數學
I will teach you,oh,economics,mathematics,
- 哲學 科學 - 讀和寫?
- philosophy,science. - To read and write?
當然
Of course.
什麼時候開始?
When do we start?
我計劃好了
I got it.I got it.
熄燈
Lights out.Lights.
讓我們檢查 快點
Let's have 'em.Come on.
洞口一天開兩次
The slot opens twice a day.
一次是拿裝髒物的垃圾桶
Once for your toilet bucket,which is where we hide the dirt.
快點
Come on.
一次是晚餐
And once in the evening for your plate.
熄燈
Lights out.Out.
快點 牧師
Come on,priest.
謝謝
Thank you.
在這期間 我們可以整天工作 不必擔心被發現
Between those times we can work all day without fear of discovery.
"所以 他們的疏忽成為了...
"So neglect becomes...
我們最好的助手"
our ally."
好極了
Excellent.
那麼 你是拿破侖的人
So you were in Napoleon's army.
我們曾經做過那樣的夢
We had such dreams then.
然而 一天夜裏...
However,one night...
我的組織崩潰了...
my regiment ran down...
一群士兵
a band of guerrillas,
跑進教堂尋求避難
who ran into a church for sanctuary.
叫我燒掉教堂...
I was ordered to burn...down the church...
把他們也燒在裏面
with them inside it.
你做了?
Did you?
是我永久的恥辱 我做了
To my everlasting shame,I did.
我做了
I did.
你是怎麼來這裏的?
How did you come to be here?
第二天我離開了...
The following day I deserted...
為了用我一生的時間懺悔...
to devote my life to repentance...
向上帝懺悔
and to God.
我在一個很富有的伯爵斯帕達家
I worked as private secretary to...
我在一個很富有的伯爵斯帕達家 當私人秘書
the enormously wealthy Count Enrique Spada.
斯帕達是個很正直的人
Spada was a righteous man.
不幸的是幾年後就死了...
Sadly,a couple of years later,he died...
有人傳言說他藏了巨額財富
amidst rumors that he had hidden his limitless fortune.
- 兩星期後 我被捕了 - 為什麼?
- Two weeks later,I was arrested. - Why?
拿破侖想得到斯帕達的財富
Napoleon wanted Spada's treasure.
他不相信我對此一無所知
He did not believe that I had no idea where it was.
所以他把我仍在這裏反省
So he had me thrown in here to refresh my memory.
我一直和唯一的神呆在一起...
And so here I've remained with only God...
做伴直到有了你
for company until he sent me you.
神沒有財富現實 牧師
God is no more real than your treasure,priest.
也許吧
Perhaps.
快點 抓住他
Ooh!Hurry.Get it.
估計一下
Compute this.
一天挖二千五百立方厘米的磚土...
2,500 cubic centimeters of rock and dust a day...
三百六十五天
for 365 days.
平均一年三點五平方米
Equals three-and-a-half meters a year,
十二英尺 一月一尺
12 feet,a foot a month.
一星期三英吋
Three inches a week.
在意大利
In Italian.
不要浪費光
Do not waste the light.
你是個軍人 牧師
You were a soldier,priest.
那麼你懂武器
So you know weaponry.
教我
Teach me.
否則你自己挖
Or dig alone.
你逼我走上了這條路 唐太斯
You force me to walk a fine line,Dantes.
真可笑
This is ridiculous.
出色的劍客不一定要贏
The stronger swordsman does not necessarily win.
是速度!
It is speed!
手的速度
Speed of hand.
腦的速度
Speed of mind.
現在 讓手掠過水滴...
Now,sweep your hand through the drops...
不能打濕
without getting wet.
像這樣
Like this.
要練多久?
How long must I keep this up?
我要下隧道了
I am going down the tunnel.
要有力度
Parry.Up.
像這樣
Like that.
該學習了
Time to study.
定義經濟學
Define economics.
經濟是一門處理日用品的生產
Economics is the science that deals with the production,
分配 消費關係的科學
distribution and consumption of commodities.
翻譯
Translation.
勞動第一 金錢第二
Dig first,money later.
謝謝 聖誕快樂 愛德蒙
Thank you.Happy Christmas,Edmond.
大概一個月左右
Give or take a month or so.
好 你要跟誰戰鬥?騰格拉爾?蒙德哥?
Good.Whom are you fighting?Danglars?Mondego?
你認為該是誰?
Who do you think?
好 很好
Good!Too good.
我們用牛頓第三定律
We have Newton's third law.
每個行為都會有反映...
There is a reaction to every action...
物理反映...人類
in physics...and in man.
我要報仇就是對騰格拉爾和蒙德哥行為的反映
Thus my quest for vengeance is a reaction to the actions of Danglars and Mondego.
起來 起來
Up,up.
我要坐
I want that seat.
你曾對我說維爾福釋放了你在...
You once told me that Villefort had you rearrested just after...
他清楚了你所有的控訴之後
he had cleared you of all the charges.
你可以走了
You may go.
的確是那樣
Yes,that's true.
那麼為什麼他又言而無信呢...
Then why would he go through that charade...
除非有讓他改變放你走的理由?
unless he had reason to change his mind about letting you go?
- 想想愛德蒙. - 我在想
- Think,Edmond. - I'm trying.
- 有嗎? - 他問我- -
- What happened? - He asked me...
拿破侖有沒有告訴過你 誰會取那封信?
Did Napoleon tell you who was supposed to pick up this letter?
- 我告訴他- - - 一個叫諾瓦蒂斯的先生
- I told him... - A Monsieur Clarion.
- 沒別的嗎? - 沒有 他燒了信後說我可以走了
- And nothing more? - Nothing.He burnt the letter and said I could go.
他燒了...信
He burned...the letter.
是的
Yes.
奇怪 那個官員怎麼會燒燬...
Strange that a chief magistrate would burn evidence...
叛國陰謀的罪證...
of a treasonous conspiracy...
並且監禁了唯一...
and then imprison the only man...
知道諾瓦蒂埃先生
who was aware of Monsieur Clarion's connection...
與那個陰謀有關的人
to that conspiracy.
- 他是在保護什麼人 - 嗯
- He was protecting someone. - Ah.
- 也許是個親密的朋友? - 不 不
- A dear friend perhaps? - No.No.
像維爾福這樣的政治家 不會有這樣的朋友
A politician like Villefort would have rid himself of such friends.
諾瓦蒂斯是個親戚
Clarion could be a relative.
可能是個很親的親人- -
A close relative,possibly...
不
No!
維爾福父親 曾是拿破侖軍隊的陸軍上校
Villefort's father was a colonel in Napoleon's army.
維爾福不是保護諾瓦蒂斯
Villefort wasn't protecting Clarion.
是在保護自己
He was protecting himself.
騰格拉爾假裝說 他看見拿破侖給了我信
Danglars,who falsely said he saw Napoleon give me that letter.
蒙德哥 告訴維爾福我有信
Mondego,who told Villefort I had it.
維爾福把我送到這裏
And Villefort himself,who sent me here.
好 愛德蒙 好
Bravo,Edmond,bravo.
哦 天啊 哦
Oh,my God.Oh,oh.
哦
Oh.
愛德蒙 燈 燈 快點 燈
Edmond,light.Light.Quick.Light.
哦 拜託 天啊 那是什麼?看
Oh,please,God.What is that?Look.
看 看 根 植物的根
Look.Look!Roots.Plant roots.
如果這是植物的根 那麼我們就只有幾個月了
If these are plant roots,then we are only months away.
是 太好了 牧師 我去拿鑿子
Yes.Well done,priest.I'll get my chisel.
好 好
Good.Good.
牧師
Priest!
看在上帝的份上 繼續下去
In God's name,go on.
繼續 繼續
Go on.Go on!
肺砸傷了
Lungs...are punctured.
- 別說話 別說話 - 聽著
- Don't talk.Don't talk. - Listen.
時間不多了
There's not much time.
書底下
Under th-those books,
有塊松石塊
there's loose rocks.
找來給我
Bring me what you find.
快點
Quickly,quickly.
打開
Open it.
我告訴他們我不知道...
When I told them I did not know...
斯帕達的財富在哪裏 是我撒謊
where the treasure of Spada was,I lied.
你撒謊?
You lied?
我是牧師 不是聖人
I'm a priest,not a saint.
那裏
There,
在那個靠近意大利海濱的島上
on that island off the Italian coast.
- 蒙特科瑞斯特? - 對 對
- Monte Cristo? - Yes,yes.
動腦筋
Use...Use your head.
- 沿著線索 - 地道堵住了 我逃不了
- Follow the clues. - The tunnel's blocked.I can't escape.
不 繼續挖
No,keep digging.
逃出去後 好好利用它 要做善事
When you escape,use it for good,only for good.
不 我要用它報仇
No,I will surely use it for my revenge.
這是你的最後一課
Here now is your final lesson.
不要犯...
Do not commit...
不要犯罪
Oh.Do not commit the crime...
那樣你會判刑的
for which you now serve the sentence.
上帝說 "復仇在我"
God said,"Vengeance is mine."
我不相信上帝
I don't believe in God.
沒關係
That doesn't matter.
相信你自己
He believes in you.
牧師?
Priest?
盤子拿出來
Plates out.
吃飯了
Let's have it.
哦
Oh.
哦 天哪
Oh,God.
他從未睡過覺
He's always awake.
這是十二年來第一次 他沒說"謝謝"
First time in 12 years he hasn't said "thank you."
- 死了- 怎麼死的?
- Dead. - How?
從床上摔下來的 不是嗎?
Fell off his bed,didn't he?
- 他有點髒 不是嗎? - 他們都很髒
- He's a bit dirty,isn't he? - They all are.
嗯 把他裝上...
Well,let's sew him up...
然後去見朵裏克
and then see Dorleac.
一 二 三
One,two,three.
好了 我們去找朵裏克
Right,let's get Dorleac.
為什麼不綁好 他不會跑了
Why'd you lock it?He's not going anywhere.
我不知道
I don't know.Habit,I suppose.
再見 牧師
Good-bye,priest.
現在你自由了
You're free now,
我永遠無法自由
as I will never be.
老牧師死了
So the old pope has finally gone to St.Peter's.
把他帶走
Well,bring him along.
- 要不把他埋了 - 準備好沒?
- Let's bury him,then. - You ready?
一 真重
One.That's it.
- 往前走 - 快點 快點 我們不想花一整天的時間
- Keep going. - Come on,come on.I haven't got all day.
實際上 我無所謂
Actually,I do.
我有- -
I've got...
我有的是時間
I've got all the time in the world!
過來
Come on.
朵裏克先生
Monsieur Dorleac!
神父 我們會把您的意旨.
Heavenly Father,we bequeath to you...
傳給這些卑微的僕人
these remains of your humble servant.
無論他叫什麼
Whatever his name was.
天 我是多麼無聊
God,I'm so bored.
朵裏克先生
Monsieur Dorleac!
他真的有一張藏寶圖嗎?
Did he,in fact,have a map?
沒有
No,gov.
- - - 在哪裏?
Where's the,uh...
停下
Stop!
朵裏克先生
Monsieur Dorleac!
三聲後 是什麼意思?我們數到三 還是數到三之前把他扔下去?
What do you mean,after three?We throw him at three or before three?
三聲後
After three.
- 朵裏克先生! - 那...
- Monsieur Dorleac! - And th...
- 不要 朵裏克先生! - 一...
- Don't,Mr.Dorleac! - One...
- 二... - 不要把屍體扔下懸崖
- two... - Don't throw the body over the cliff!
- 啊! - 三!
- Aah! - Three!
我們本來可以處理的更好點
We could have handled that a bit better.
謝謝你 牧師
Thank you,priest.
謝謝你
Thank you.
那麼 小子
So,mi amice,
我本想問你是誰 但從你那破爛的衣服看...
I would ask who you are,but in view of your shredded clothes...
實際上伊夫堡監獄離這不過兩英里
and the fact that the Chateau d'lf is two miles away,
你想說什麼?
what's the point?
至於我 我叫 魯伊蓋 瓦帕 走私犯和盜賊
As for me,I am Luigi Vampa,a smuggler and a thief.
我的同夥和我來這個島 活埋我們中的一個同伴...
My men and I have come to this island to bury alive one of our number...
他企圖私藏盜來的金子...
who attempted to keep some stolen gold for himself...
而不是和他的同夥分享
instead of,uh,sharing it with his comrades.
有趣地是 他有很多忠實的朋友...
Interestingly enough,there are some of his more loyal friends...
他們要讓對他我仁慈一點
who are insisting that I grant him mercy,
當然 我不會
which,of course,I cannot do,
因為我會失去對全局的控制
for I would quickly lose control of the whole crew.
- 那就是你被發現的原因 - 是什麼?
- That's why you are such a fortunate find. - Why is that?
你給我提供一個 對雅格布仁慈一點的方法
You provide me with a way to show a little mercy to Jacopo,
就是綁在那邊的傢伙
that maggot you see tied up over there,
但 同時 要合情合理
while,at the same time,not appearing weak.
特殊一點 夥計們也要要看到一點武鬥場面
And as a special treat,the lads will get to see a little sport as well.
我要怎麼做?
How do I accomplish all this?
我們看你和雅格布搏鬥直到死
We watch you and Jacopo fight to the death.
如果雅格布贏了 我們歡迎他回來
If Jacopo wins,we welcome him back to the crew.
如果你贏了我會給雅格布活的機會
If you win,I have given Jacopo the chance to live,
如果他沒有佔優勢
even if he did not take advantage of it,
你就代替他在船上的位置
and you can take his place on the boat.
如果我贏了又不想成為走私犯呢?
What if I win,and I don't want to be a smuggler?
那麼我們會割破你的喉嚨 也就少了一個幫手
Then we slit your throat,and we're a bit shorthanded.
我發現走私是我命中注定的...
I find that smuggling is the life for me...
我情願殺了你的朋友 那個可惡的傢伙
and would be delighted to kill your friend,the maggot.
順便說一聲 雅格布是我見過的最好的刀斗好手
Oh,uh,by the way,Jacopo is the best knife fighter I've ever seen.
或許你應該離遠點
Perhaps you should get out more.
鬆開雅格布 給他刀
Release Jacopo and give him back his knife.
那麼 開始吧
Then we let the games begin.
起來 傢伙
Get up,maggot.
- 上 上
Come on,come on!
如果你想活 就不要動一根睫毛
As you hope to live,do not move an eyelash.
瓦帕先生 讓雅格布活
Senor Vampa,allow Jacopo to live.
他已經受夠了被活埋的恐懼
He's already suffered enough with the prospect of being buried alive.
他想他該看到的已經看到了
The men that wanted to see some sport have seen it.
對雅格布表示同情的人會明白
Those who wanted mercy for Jacopo will get it.
留下我和雅格布
And by keeping me and Jacopo,
你又會有個為你的隊伍效力的好水手和鬥士
you will have yet another skilled sailor and fighter for your crew.
就這樣
It's a deal.
- 他叫什麼? - 你碰到對手了雅格布!
- What is his name? - You've got the devil,Jacopo!
他的名字?我們叫他扎特爾
His name?We shall call him Zatarra.
- 聽起來很可怕 - 他的意思是無用的人
- Sounds fearsome. - It means driftwood.
我對天發誓
I swear on my dead relatives,
雖然那些日子很糟
even on the ones that are not feeling too good,
我永遠是你的人
I am your man forever.
我知道
I know.
眼睛可以看到一切
Eyes in the back of your head.
以前到過馬賽嗎?
Have you never seen Marseilles before?
那是我的家
It was my home.
但你沒到過其他的海岸
But you do not join the others ashore.
- 這裏 - 聽我說 扎特爾
- Over here! - Listen to me,Zatarra.
無論你曾經發生過什麼 你不能呆在這個船上弄明白
Whatever happened to you,you cannot make it right by staying here on this boat.
走 由你決定
Go.It's up to you.
"我們要麼是統治者 要麼被統治"有人曾經說過
"We are kings or pawns," a man once said.
誰告訴你的?
Si.Who told you this?
拿破侖.波拿巴
Napoleon Bonaparte.
波拿巴
Bonaparte?
扎特爾 這就是你說的故事
Oh,Zatarra,the stories you tell.
有一天我會來找你
Someday I may come to find you.
人總是需要好朋友
A man is always in need of a good friend.
的確是這樣
Truly.
騰格拉爾發生了什麼事
Danglars,what's happened?
萊克勒船長死了 先生 愛德蒙·唐太斯不聽我的話
Captain Reynaud is dead,sir,and Edmond Dantes disobeyed my orders.
扎特爾 你好嗎?
Zatarra,are you all right?
什麼都變了
Everything's changed.
我要你去買一條船 只是兩個人控制的
I want you to buy a boat,just something the two of us can handle.
等我回來 我要單獨看看
Wait for me to return.I make my next visit alone.
莫雷爾先生的家嗎?
Is...Is this the home of Monsieur Morell?
祖父的身體不太好 先生
My grandfather isn't well,monsieur.
即使他在 也不接見晚上十一點鐘來的客人
Even if he were,he would not receive visitors at 11:00 in the evening.
或許有例外...
Perhaps he might make an exception...
為了一個 尋找愛德蒙·唐太斯的人
for a man who is seeking E-Edmond Dantes.
抱歉這麼晚打擾
I apologize for the hour.
老人這時不會睡 請坐
Old people never sleep.Sit down,sit down.
- 朱利娜 拿些葡萄酒
Julianne,some sherry.
扎特爾先生
So,Monsieur Zatarra,
你是愛德蒙的朋友嗎?
you were a friend of Edmond?
- 莫雷爾先生? - 什麼?
- Monsieur Morell? - Yes?
你也認識愛德蒙?
You knew...Edmond also?
像他的兒子
Like a son.
我希望你能告訴我 在哪能找到他的家?
I was hoping you could tell me where to find his family.
不幸的是 他上吊自殺了...
Unfortunately,his father hanged himself...
得知愛德蒙是叛國罪之後
after learning of Edmond's treason.
我明白了
I see.
我明白
至於...
And...
你提到的叛國罪
this...treason you speak of...
- 誰告的他? - 誰知道呢?
- Who accused him? - Who knows?
維爾福先生 逮捕愛德蒙的那個人
Monsieur Villefort,the man who had Edmond arrested,
不久就去了巴黎勝任...
left for Paris soon after to take up the post...
檢察官的職務
of chief prosecutor.
當然 他爸爸被暴力謀殺的震撼...
Of course,the shock of his father's violent murder...
也許加快了他的起程
may also have spurred his departure.
他們不是一個時代的
They were strange times.
你似乎處境很艱難 先生
You seem to have fallen on difficult times yourself,sir.
愛德蒙死後 我勉強接受了一個合夥人
After Edmond's death,I reluctantly took on a partner.
一個船長
One of my captains.
然而一天 騰格拉爾逼我退出
And then one day,Danglars forced me out.
我的命運跟愛德蒙相比算不了什麼
My fate is nothing compared to Edmond's.
也許改變是一種幸運
Perhaps your luck is about to change.
我要找到愛德蒙的未婚妻
I shall search out Edmond's fiancee.
你是說 蒙德哥伯爵夫人
You mean the Countess Mondego?
- 伯爵夫人? - 是的
- Countess? - Yes.
可憐的愛德蒙被捕一個月後
A month after poor Edmond was arrested,
美塞苔絲嫁給了他最好的朋友
Mercedes wed his best friend.
- 費爾南多. - 對 是他
- Fernand. - Yes,that's right.
他的爸爸和弟弟在戰爭中死了
And with the death of his father and brother in the war,
費爾南多成了蒙德哥伯爵
Fernand became Count Mondego.
他們現在住在巴黎
They live in Paris now.
蒙德哥伯爵和伯爵夫人
Count and Countess Mondego.
你沒事吧?
Are you all right?
沒事 我要走了
Yes.I must go.
- 抱歉 我不能給你幫助 - 不
- I'm sorry I was not more helpful. - Oh,no.
你說了我想知道的
You told me what I needed to know.
愛德蒙·唐太斯死了
Edmond Dantes is dead.
扎特爾 扎特爾 你會為我而自豪的
Zatarra.Zatarra,you will be so proud of me.
我找到了一條漂亮的小船 我們買不起單桅帆船
I found a nice little skiff.We couldn't afford a sloop.
真的很划算 扎特爾?
Got a really good deal.Za-Zatarra?
扎特爾
Zatarra.
哇~!
Whoo-hoo!
扎特爾 船不能再裝了
Zatarra,the boat cannot hold no more,
至少還要八條來裝
and there are at least eight more boatloads down there!
你不明白嗎?
Do you not understand?
你比我聽說的任何人都富有
You are wealthier than any man I have ever heard of.
無論什麼問題都解決了
Whatever your problems were,they are over.
你想買什麼?
What do you want to buy?
報仇
Revenge.
好 報仇 誰?
Okay,revenge.Who?
騰格拉爾 維爾福
Danglars,Villefort,
費爾南多和美塞苔絲
Fernand and Mercedes.
好
Right.
我們殺了這些人 然後再花錢
We kill these people,then we spend the treasure.
不 我們要研究他們 找到他們的弱點
No,we will study them,learn their weaknesses.
為什麼不簡單的殺了他們?我去
Why not just kill them?I'll do it.
我去巴黎
I'll run up to Paris...bam,bam,bam,bam!
我會在週末之前回來 然後我們花錢
I'm back before week's end.We spend the treasure.
這個計劃怎麼樣?
How is this a bad plan?
死太便宜他們了
Death is too good for them.
他們必須遭受和我一樣的痛苦
They must suffer as I suffered.
他們要看到他們的世界 所擁有的所有美好的東西
They must see their world,all they hold dear,
從他們身邊剝奪 就像從我身上奪走的一樣
ripped from them as it was ripped from me.
你需要一個比扎特爾更好的名字 如果你想達到目的
You will need a better name than Zatarra if you are to accomplish that.
我要成為伯爵
Then I shall become a count.
下午快樂 先生
I bid you good afternoon,sir.
我來著兒想購買你美麗的家園
I'm here to purchase your lovely home.
厚顏無恥 滾走吧
The very cheek!I shall have you horsewhipped!
現在 拿走我的財產 懶漢
Now,get off my property,you vagabond,
在我放狗咬你之前 聽到了嗎?
before I set the dogs on you,you hear?
謝謝
Thank you.
女士們 先生們
Ladies and gentlemen,
非常榮幸向各位介紹閣下
it is with great honor that I present to you His Grace,
基督山伯爵
the Count of Monte Cristo.
真是太美了
It's so beautiful.
晚上好
Greetings.
親愛的伯爵 請允許我介紹我丈夫
My dear count,allow me to introduce to you my husband,
維爾福先生 檢察官
Monsieur Villefort,Chief Prosecutor.
能想到我們你真好
Very kind of you to think of us.
你們能出席我很榮幸
Oh,I am the one honored with your presence.
今晚玩得高興
Now,please,enjoy yourselves tonight.
我們瞭解他多少?
What do we know about him?
不多
Not enough.
他們在哪裏??你確信你請了他們?
Where are they?Are you sure you invited them?
是 閣下
Yes,Your Grace.
但我剛剛知道蒙德哥伯爵已經走了
But I just learned that Count Mondego has retired for the evening.
他有個早約會不能錯過
He has a morning appointment he cannot miss.
起這麼早 親愛的
You're up early,my dear.
徒威爾子爵死了嗎?
Is the Viscount Tourville dead?
除非他的心臟不在左心房
Unless his heart is situated somewhere other than the left side of his chest,
我想他會死
I suspect he is.
上帝保佑他平安無事
God grant him peace.
他只不過在維護他家族的尊嚴
He did no more than defend his family's honor.
我對他很仁慈了
Much good it did him.
他的妻子和我都會高興 你也會為你的無知感到高興
His wife and I were happy in our passion.You were happy in your ignorance.
現在子爵維護了他家族的尊嚴
Now comes the viscount's valiant defense of his honor,
你痛苦了
and you are pained.
- 她破產了 他死了 - 不要高估了自己
- She is ruined,and he is dead. - Don't flatter yourself.
我即不高興也不無知
I was neither happy nor ignorant,
認識徒威爾太太之前 我才認識三個女人
having known about the last three women before Madame Tourville.
我為你的羞辱感到難過
I'm sorry you are humiliated.
我和巴黎的融合就是個錯誤
The combination of Paris and me is hardly a recipe for fidelity.
我試圖找我錯在哪裏
And since my attempts at discretion have evidently failed,
看起來像在給自己找借口
there seems little point in keeping up pretenses.
實際上 真是太自由了
It's actually quite...liberating.
你說呢?
Wouldn't you say?
他的未婚妻?
His finances?
他賭博輸了很多錢
He's losing money at the other casinos.
他們甚至不用欺騙他
They're not even cheating him.
調查過他的海運嗎?
Have you looked into his shipping?
七年前為了他的船隻向銀行貸款
He got a bank loan for his own boat several years ago.
- 沒有用騰格拉爾的錢嗎 - 我們欠銀行的錢明天就到期了
- Doesn't use Danglars. - Make sure we own that bank by tomorrow.
告訴其他的船運公司 不要支援蒙德哥
Tell the other shipping companies to stay away from Mondego.
我要讓他走投無路 爬著去求騰格拉爾
I want to give him no choice but to crawl back to Danglars.
現在去告訴船商
Now,tell the dealers...take it all.
很想知道
Do try to understand.
我有一大批棉花就要運出
I have a very large consignment of cotton ready to be sent,
我會盡快用它支付船費
and I shall make my payment on the ship as soon as it is delivered.
顯然 我需要船裝運
So obviously I need the vessel in order to deliver it.
很不幸 銀行不能提供更多的貸款 蒙德哥伯爵
Unfortunately,the bank can offer no further extensions,Count Mondego.
我建議你尋找其他的辦法
I suggest you find alternate means of shipping.
很榮幸 蒙德哥伯爵?
Well,well.To what do I owe the honor,Count Mondego?
不明白為什麼這些天你總躲著我
Can't imagine why you've been avoiding me after all these years.
我不想責怪你犯的錯誤...
I'm prepared to overlook your faults...
也許我們可以再次合作
and perhaps resume our dealings.
最近生意不好嗎?
Business not going so well these days?
扎特爾?
Zatarra?
雅格布
Jacopo.
你掉下了床嗎?
Did you fall off the bed?
睡了十三年的石板 不習慣睡床
After 13 years of sleeping on a stone slab,I can't.
那傷?
Mi Maria.Does that hurt?
有事嗎?
Did you come here for a reason?
蒙德哥有個兒子
Mondego has a son.
- 想跟我們談談 - 現在沒空
- Albert wishes to talk with us. - Not now!
告訴他我會給他留下遺產
Tell him I'm trying to protect his inheritance.
你擔心他會像你一樣把它揮霍掉嗎?
Are you afraid he's going to squander his as you have yours?
當我把你從一個魚販的女兒提高身價後 我不想聽你的嘮叨了
I don't recall hearing your complaints when I elevated you from a fishmonger's daughter.
我必須忙完事 然後出去
Please,I must finish this,then I shall be going out.
我要提醒你 親愛的 巴黎也許有很多情婦
May I remind you,my love,that in Paris there are mistresses aplenty,
但你只有一個兒子
but you have only one son.
進來 阿爾貝
Come in,Albert.
- 看在上帝的份上 簡單點 - 我會的 父親
- For God's sake,be brief. - I will,Father.
我的幾個朋友 要去羅馬過兩個星期的狂歡節
Several of my friends are going to Rome for two weeks during Carnival.
- 我想跟他們一起去 - 羅馬?
- I would like to accompany them. - Rome?
- 不要帶女伴 你才十五歲 - 快十六了
- And no chaperons?You're only 15. - Almost 16.
父親 請在我的生日上宣佈好嗎?
Make it my birthday present,Father,please.
- 我不想惹麻煩 - 不
- I won't get into trouble. - No.
當然他可以去 現在我需要安靜
Of course he can go.I could do with some peace and quiet around here.
羅馬
Rome!
阿爾貝!阿爾貝!
Albert!Albert!
- 這裏 這裏 - 這裏
- Over here!Over here! - Over here!
小姐?
Milady?
不要藏起來
Can't hide forever.
小姐?
Milady?
你們是什麼人?想幹什麼?
Who are you,and why are you doing this?
- 我們是惡人 為了錢 - 錢在我的馬甲裏
- We are bad men,and for the money. - My money is in my waistcoat.
不是很多 還有 我們對別人的錢不感興趣
Not anymore.Besides,it's not your money we're interested in.
你是蒙德哥伯爵唯一的兒子 是嗎?
You are the only son of Count Mondego,are you not?
贖金?寄封信就夠了
Ransom?Send your note and be damned.
我也想這麼簡單 但兩星期你爸爸才能受到信
I wish it were that easy,but a note won't reach your father for two weeks,
那時不知我們 是不是已經把你殺了
and then there's the endless debates about whether we killed you already.
信沒用 或許我們要把你的戒指送給他
No,a note just doesn't have the impact.Perhaps if we send him your ring.
是 我的戒指有蒙德哥的標誌
Yes.My ring bears the Mondego crest.
還連著你的手指嗎?
While still attached to your finger?
聽我說 強盜
Listen to me,vermin.
我叫阿爾貝 是蒙德哥伯爵的兒子
I am Albert,son of Fernand,Count Mondego,
你們休想拿一分錢
and you have had your last laugh at my expense.
- 使出你們的絕招吧 - 如果你堅持 拿刀來
- Do your worst. - If you insist.Peppone,the knife.
割斷孩子的繩子
Cut this boy's ropes,
否則不要逼我砍你們
or I will be forced to start cutting your miserable corpses.
快點
Now!
跟我來 年輕人 去看看外面?在那等我
Follow me,young man.You see the surface?Wait for me there.
- 我不知道怎麼感謝你 - 走吧 呆會兒再談
- I don't know how to thank you. - Go.We'll talk later.
幹得好 各位
Well done,gentlemen.
非常感謝 閣下
Many thanks,Your Grace.
阿爾貝
Albert.
你沒事吧?
Are you all right?
閣下 我欠你一條命
Sir,I owe you my life.
你很勇敢
You've had quite an ordeal.
你是個非凡的年輕人
You're an extraordinary young man.
明天你一定要到我家來吃早飯
I insist,you must come to my estate for breakfast tomorrow.
好嗎?
Agreed?
好
Agreed.
我可以知道你是誰嗎 閣下?
May I ask who you are,sir?
今天是你的朋友 明天是你的主人
For the present,your friend.Tomorrow,your host.
短時間我們就建立了友誼
For the short time formality stands between us,
基督山伯爵
the Count of Monte Cristo.
他在外面的侯客室
He's out in the waiting room.
在地道他表現的很有勇氣
He showed courage in the tunnels.
他是達到目的的工具
He's a means to an end.
是 閣下
Yes,Your Grace.
年輕人
Young man.
阿爾貝 進來 來 來
Albert,come in.Come,come.
過來
Come on.
- 昨晚還好吧 - 是的
- You've had quite a night. - Yes.
一次冒險
What an adventure.
當你年輕時 凡事都在冒險
Everything's an adventure when you're young.
- 有件事我不明白 閣下
- One thing puzzles me,sir. - Hmm.
你怎麼知道我被綁架了
How did you come to know of my kidnapping?
我有很多耳目
I have many connections,
一些都是很有名的
some of which are less than reputable.
我花了很多錢打聽 我所在城市發生的任何事
I pay well to be informed of anything of note in any city in which I stay.
伯爵兒子的綁架當然就知道了
And the kidnapping of a count's son is of note.
但為什麼冒著生命危險救我
But why risk your life rescuing me?
你是朋友的兒子
The son of a fellow noble.
小事罷了
It was the least I could do.
以你的性格 你也會這麼做的
Judging by your character,I'm sure you would have done the same.
你父親會以你為榮的
Your father will be proud of you.
你一定要到巴黎見我的父母 以便他們能親自感謝你
You must come to Paris and meet my parents so they may thank you in person.
很遺憾 我不能去 你知道 我還有生意
Unfortunately,I cannot.Business,you see.
你去是我的榮幸
Please,it is a matter of honor.
- 雅格布? - 在 閣下
- Jacopo? - Yes,Your Grace?
斯帕達之事- - 我們的貨在哪裏?
The Spada matter...where do we stand?
- 現在 金子- - 貨船?
- Even now,the gold... - The shipment?
抱歉 閣下 貨船正在運輸中
Oh,I-I'm sorry,Your Grace.The shipment is in transit,
正開往馬賽
uh,bound for Marseilles.
- 到了嗎? - 還要三個星期閣下
- And it arrives? - Not for another three weeks,Your Grace.
三星期?有足夠的時間參觀巴黎
Three weeks?That's more than enough time to visit in Paris.
- 好吧 - 太好了
- Very well. - Excellent.
- 你會及時到那裏嗎? - 為什麼要及時?
- And you'll be there just in time. - In time for?
- 生日快樂 - 謝謝
- Happy birthday. - Thanks.
基督山伯爵
The Count of Monte Cristo.
伯爵
Count!
- 阿爾貝. - 閣下 父親
- Albert. - Your Grace.Father!
讓我介紹基督山伯爵
May I present the Count of Monte Cristo.
- 很榮幸 - 是我的榮幸 蒙德哥伯爵
- 'Tis a pleasure. - The pleasure is mine,Count Mondego.
我期待這一刻很久了
I've been looking forward to this moment for some time.
您太客氣了 我非常感謝你...
You do me much honor,when it is I who are indebted to you...
救了我的兒子
for the rescue of my son.
請允許我介紹蒙德哥伯爵夫人
May I present the Countess Mondego.
美塞苔絲
Mercedes.
伯爵夫人
Countess.
你一定很善良...
You would have to be a mother to truly appreciate the service...
你為我和我兒子做的一切
you've done for my son and me.
先生 我會記住的
Monsieur,I shall never forget you.
夫人 請不要
Please,madame,
不足掛齒
it was nothing.
我敢說一個月之後 你會忘了我的名字
I am sure that within a month,you will not even remember my name.
嗯?
Hmm?
我可以借用一下你的妻子嗎?
May I steal your wife?
- 你說什麼? - 跳華爾茲
- I'm sorry? - For the waltz.
當然可以
Of course.
他很了不起吧 父親?
Isn't he wonderful,Father?
- 有事嗎? - 沒有
- What's the matter? - Uh,nothing.
你讓我想起了很久以前的一個人
You just remind me of someone from long ago,
他對我很重要
someone who was very dear to me.
我很榮幸 他發生了什麼事?
I'm flattered.What happened to him?
他死了
He died.
但我不是他
But I'm not that man.
維爾福先生和夫人
Monsieur and Madame Villefort.
他們來這幹什麼?
What are they doing here?
檢察官維爾福
Prosecutor Villefort.
- 你來這裏幹什麼? - 維爾福夫人 維爾福先生
- What are you doing here? - Oh,Madame Villefort,monsieur.
很高興你們來看我
I'm so glad you could come to see me while I'm still in town.
- 收到你的請貼我們很驚喜 - 謝謝
- We were delightfully surprised to get your note. - Thank you.
我可以佔用你丈夫的一點時間嗎
Would you be so kind as to excuse your husband and I for a moment?
在法律方面你是個行家
I'm told you are an expert in the interpretation of the law.
有件事 也許你能幫我
I have a certain matter that perhaps you could help me with.
對不起
Excuse me.
費爾南多.費爾南多!祝詞!
Fernand.Fernand!The toast!
現在不行 我有生意要忙
Not right now.I have state business to attend to.
客人都等著 阿爾貝也等著
Our guests expect it.Albert expects it.
你講吧 親愛的 一定會很精彩
You give it,my dear.I'm sure it'll be splendid.
你是他的父親
You are his father!
你也能行 知道他有多麼崇拜你
It is the least you can do.You know how he admires you.
他會原諒我的缺席
Then he will forgive my absence.
但- -
But...
我認為我們不應該在公共場合見面
I thought we agreed not to meet socially.
我怎麼能拒絕基督山伯爵呢?
How could I pass up the Count of Monte Cristo?
的確
Quite.
- 他怎麼樣? - 他是外地人
- What do you know of him? - He's foreign,
很有錢
rich.
我聽說他救了你兒子
I hear he aided your son.
- 為什麼他向你咨詢? - 為什麼要告訴你
- Why does he seek your counsel? - Why should I tell you?
我兒子從羅馬回來時
When my son returned from Rome,
他提到他聽見基督山說他在等貨船
he mentioned he'd heard Monte Cristo saying he was expecting a shipment.
他也聽到了一個"金"字...
He also heard the words "gold"...
和"斯帕達"
and "Spada."
- 嗯 - 你不相信- -
- Hmm. - You don't believe...
基督山找到了斯帕達財寶
Monte Cristo has found the treasure of Spada.
剛才 他叫我幫他避開檢查的麻煩...
Not an hour ago,he asked me to help him avoid troublesome inspections...
開往馬賽的一艘貨船
on a shipment coming from Marseilles.
- 嗯 - 我可以把他逮捕
- Hmm. - I could have him arrested.
不要那樣做 我們就幫他解決問題
Don't do that.Let's just relieve him of it.
- 你怎麼計劃的- - - 我有個管這類事的熟人
- How do you propose... - I have an acquaintance who deals in these matters.
告訴基督山你會讓貨船順利通過海關
Tell Monte Cristo you'll get his shipment through Customs,
但船必須在港口停一夜
but that it will have to stay in port overnight.
我把它移到我的老家
I shall have it removed and taken to my old family estate in Bouchon,
第二天 我們在那裏碰頭
where we shall meet the following day.
我要百分之七十
I require 70 percent.
你只能要百分之五十
And yet you'll only get 50.
成交
Done.
是 那是 不是嗎?
Yes,it is,isn't it?
好 我知道 好 知道了
Yes,well,I know.Yes.
女士們 先生們
Ladies and gentlemen,
很抱歉 我因為生意走不開
unfortunately,my husband has been detained by business.
所以就由我- -
And so it is left up to me to...
給大家介紹...
To introduce you...
再次介紹基督山伯爵
to the Count of Monte Cristo yet again.
我要請求伯爵的原諒...
You see,I had the audacity to beg the count...
請允許我為阿爾貝獻上生日祝詞
to allow me to give the birthday toast to Albert.
我一定要這麼做 這是主人的恩賜
I was so insistent,and such is the graciousness of our host,
他不得不放棄做為父親的權利...
that he reluctantly gave up his fatherly right...
為了招待
in order to accommodate a guest,
和我一樣俗氣的客人
even one as boorish as myself.
年輕的阿爾貝太客氣了...
Young Albert has made far too much...
對我在羅馬給他的幫助
of the assistance I gave him in Rome.
當我趕大地道時
When I arrived in the catacombs,
我見罪犯把阿爾貝幫在牆上
I watched as the criminals,who tied Albert to a wall,
威脅說要砍掉他的手指送給他的父親...
threatened to cut off his finger and send it to his father...
作為他被幫的證物
as evidence of his abduction.
天哪
Goodness!
那孩子的回答是..."使出你們的絕招吧.
The boy's reply to all this was..."Do your worst."
生活就像暴風雨 我年輕的朋友
Life is a storm,my young friend.
今天你在陽光下享受著溫暖
You will bask in the sunlight one moment,
明天你可能被暗礁擊得粉碎
be shattered on the rocks the next.
什麼使你成為一個男人...
What makes you a man...
就是當暴風雨來時你要做的
is what you do when that storm comes.
你必須盯著它 像在羅馬那樣大聲叫到
You must look into that storm and shout,as you did in Rome,
"使出你的絕招吧...
"Do your worst...
因為我不在乎
for I will do mine."
那麼命運之神會和我們一樣懂你
Then the fates will know you as we know you,
因為阿爾貝·蒙德哥是個男人
as Albert Mondego,the man.
快跑
Giddap!
愛德蒙 維爾福告訴我你被叛死刑
Edmond,Villefort told me that you were executed.
- 他嗎? - 天哪
- Did he? - Oh,God.
- 伯爵夫人 你誤會了 回蒙德哥那去吧 - 不
- Countess,you are mistaken.Back to the Mondegos'. - No!
- 夫人 我只是考慮到你的聲譽 - 我求你 愛德蒙
- Madame,I'm only thinking of your reputation. - I beg you,Edmond.
- 我不在乎你是怎麼回來的 - 我不是愛德蒙
- I don't care how you returned. - I am not this Edmond.
不要說!不要說!不要說!
Stop it!Stop it!Stop it!
那麼 你是什麼?
So,what are you?
幽靈?鬼魂來折磨我?
A spirit?Some ghost sent to torment me?
這個愛德蒙 你愛他嗎?
This Edmond,you loved him?
是的
Yes.
愛有多久?
For how long?
我的一生
For all of my life.
他死後多久 你嫁給了伯爵?
And how long after he died before you married the count?
那是不公平的
That isn't fair.
你到家了 伯爵夫人
We've reached your home,Countess.
你是對的 你不是我的愛德蒙
You're right.You cannot be my Edmond.
該回去了 把他藏在心裏吧
Well,there you are.You said it yourself.
愛德蒙·唐太斯 死了 晚安
Edmond Dantes is dead.Good night.
伯爵夫人
Countess.
如果你再干涉我的事
If you ever again presume to interfere in my affairs,
我發誓 我會斷絕我們的一切來往
I will,I promise,finish the job I started the day we met.
知道嗎?
Do you understand?
- 我知道你瘋了 - 瘋了?
- I understand you are mad. - Mad?
我的敵人正在陷入我的圈套
My enemies are falling into my traps perfectly.
瘋了 閣下 你忽視了這些嗎
Mad,Your Grace,for ignoring this:
財富 一個愛你的美麗女人
You have a fortune,a beautiful woman who loves you.
帶著錢 帶著女人去過你自己的生活
Take the money,take the woman and live your life.
停止這個計劃 帶走屬於你的東西
Stop this plan.Take what you have won.
- 我不能 - 為什麼不?
- I can't. - Why not?
我仍然是你的人 扎特爾
I am still your man,Zatarra.
我發誓 我會保護你
I swore an oath.I will protect you.
也就是我要保護你 不能使你自己受到傷害
Even if it means I must protect you from yourself.
我送你回去
I'll drive you home now.
我走回去
I'll walk.
把這兩箱運走 我們分
Put two chests on the Pharaon for our cut.
蒙德哥永遠不會知道
Mondego will never notice.
過來 上船
Come on.Get aboard.
- 騰格拉爾? - 什麼事?
- Philippe Danglars? - Yeah?
你被指控有盜竊一商船的貨物行為
You are charged with the theft of goods from a certain merchant ship.
真可笑
This is absurd.
我們可以簡單的處理這個問題
We can resolve this matter easily.
他們會收查你的船
These men will perform a search of your vessel.
蒙德哥伯爵叫我來的
Count Mondego set me up.
我不會為他送命
But I'll not hang for him.
你是誰?
Who are you?
我是基督山伯爵 我的朋友叫我愛德蒙·唐太斯
I'm the Count of Monte Cristo.But my friends call me Edmond Dantes.
唐太斯?
Dantes?
在他能講話之前砍斷繩子
Cut him down before he can't talk.
不要那樣做 那 那已經夠了
Boy,don't do that.That's...That's too much.
我親愛的維爾福
My dear Villefort.
我希望你不要介意我打擾你一會兒
I hope you don't mind if I join you for a short while.
閣下 怎麼是你
Your Grace,I was not expecting you.
我想親自謝謝你幫我運走了貨船
I want to thank you in person for helping me with my shipment.
那 我提前就安排好了
That,yes.I-I made all the arrangements earlier.
我向你保證過不會有問題
I can promise you there'll be no more problems from our end.
很好 我想這可能是 我們漫長商務關係的開始
Excellent.I think this could be the start of a long and fruitful relationship.
說道這 我想問個問題
Speaking of which,may I pose a question?
當然 任何問題都可以
Yes,of course.Anything in the world.
我只是奇怪
I was just curious.
為什麼十六年前你告訴蒙德哥伯爵夫人"
Why did you tell Countess Mondego 16 years ago...
愛德蒙·唐太斯被叛絞刑
that Edmond Dantes had been executed?
嗯?
Hmm?
我不明白 你到底在說什麼?
Uh,I don't understand.Wh-What on earth are you talking about?
是個很簡單的問題
It's a perfectly simple question.
你怎麼知道這些事?
How do you know these things?
那是...
That's,uh...
夠了
That's quite enough.
你不知道 唐太斯從拿破侖那裏接到一封信
Whew!You don't understand.Dantes was accepting a letter from Napoleon.
- 很顯然那是叛國罪 - 但我們都知道他沒有送那封信
- That was clearly treason. - But we both know he never delivered it.
利用這種事 把一個人送進監獄罪孽很深了 但告訴- -
Packing a man off to prison with such knowledge is bad enough.But to tell...
閣下 我不知道 這種無聊的討論是不是有意思
Your Grace,I have no idea what is provoking this perverse discussion.
現在我問自己 "我的老朋友維爾福一定得到了什麼...
Now I ask myself,"What did my old friend Villefort stand to gain...
通過告訴美塞苔絲 愛德蒙·唐太斯死了
by telling Mercedes that Edmond Dantes is dead?"
答案是什麼都得不到
The answer is...absolutely nothing.
就像你說的什麼都沒有 那麼為什麼- -
Just as you say,nothing.So why...
如果我的老朋友 現在的法國檢察官
But if my old friend,now chief prosecutor of France,
沒有從這個謊言中獲益 那麼 誰得到好處呢?
doesn't gain from this lie,well,who does?
我親愛的伯爵 這裏太熱了 幾乎可以剝皮
My dear Count,it's far too hot in here and you're fully dressed.
- 我們都應離開 - 我想明顯的獲益者...
- It's time we both left. - I think the clearest beneficiary...
是費爾南多 蒙德哥伯爵
is Fernand,Count Mondego.
我不明白這個探究與我們的買賣有什麼聯繫
I don't understand what this inquisition has to do with our business relationship.
我會告訴你
I'm about to tell you.
坐下 蒙德哥
Sit down,Mondego.
我是個有野心的人 我要擴大我的野心...
I'm an ambitious man.And I have furthered these ambitions...
通過挖掘財富
by scooping up Bonapartists.
現在拿破侖勢力很猖狂
But now with Napoleon on the loose,I have,
就像我身上的一根刺
shall I say,a thorn in my side.
一旦觸動 就有危險
Once merely an irritation,now potentially lethal.
- 危險總會有的 - 那麼 問題是...
- Be lethal in turn. - Well,the problem is such...
我一人應付不來
that I,myself,cannot attend to it.
所以我給你留了個位置
So I have a proposition for you.
你父親怎麼樣?
How is your father?
不幸地是 還活著
Alive,unfortunately.
我們共同面對災難
We share the same misfortune.
記得嗎?
You remember?
為什麼門鎖了
Why is this door locked?
我要你馬上放了我
I demand that you release me from this room at once.
你已經證明你不是我的朋友
You've proved yourself no friend of mine.
你父親是拿破侖的忠實擁護者 不是嗎?
Your father was a loyal supporter of Napoleon,wasn't he?
很可能與拿破侖從厄爾巴島逃走的陰謀有關
Possibly involved in plotting Napoleon's escape from Elba.
皇帝就要到了!
The emperor arrives soon!
一個頑固的父親 一個野心勃勃的官員
An inconvenient parent for an ambitious civil servant.
但那時 他死了 突然被謀殺了 十六年前
But then he died,suddenly and opportunely murdered,again some 16 years ago.
拿破侖皇帝
The Emperor Napoleon.
兇手沒有找到 你找得很辛苦?
The murderer never apprehended.How hard did you look for him?
你沒有證據 沒有證人
You have no proof,no witnesses.
你只有推測 只有猜想
You just have theories.J-Just conjectures.
正相反 我有蒙德哥伯爵
On the contrary.I have Count Mondego.
年輕的蒙德哥 為什麼?
Young Mondego.Why?
因為你兒子缺乏勇氣
Because your son lacked the courage.
蒙德哥就是那個開槍的人
Mondego is the one who pulled the trigger!
這麼久了他從沒有承認過
He'd never confess in a million years!
你說對了 他不會
You're right,he wouldn't.
但你已經承認了
But you just have.
維爾福先生 你因故意謀殺被捕
Monsieur Villefort,you are under arrest for conspiracy to murder.
你記起來了嗎?
You remember?
唐太斯?
Dantes?
紳士是禮節
A courtesy for a gentleman.
你不要以為這麼快就結束了?
You didn't think I'd make it that easy,did you?
駕!
Hyah!
愛德蒙?
Edmond?
我想我們的談話 在馬車裏已經結束了
I thought we had finished our conversation in the carriage.
我也想這樣
So did I.
直到我意識到...
Until I realized...
你說了"唐太斯."這個名字
you said the name "Dantes."
一個我不曾提起的名字
A name that I had never mentioned.
你想我怎麼樣?
What do you want of me?
我想擺脫你
I want to be free of you,
就像你擺脫我一樣
the way you obviously are free of me.
就問幾個問題 我就永遠消失
Just a few answers from you,and I shall be gone forever.
問吧
Ask your questions.
你在哪裏?
Where have you been?
在伊夫堡裏呆了十三年
Thirteen years in the Chateau d'lf...
你可以設想一下其他的地方
and everywhere else you can imagine.
伊夫堡呆了十三年
The Chateau d'lf for 13 years.
受苦了嗎?
Did you suffer?
完了嗎 現在 我還有很多事
Are you finished now?I have a good deal on my mind.
- 後來發生什麼事? - 很多
- What happened afterward? - Much.
- 為什麼不來找我? - 為什麼你不等我?
- Why did you not come to me? - Why did you not wait?
你嫁給了那個出賣我的人
You married the very man who betrayed...
那晚在石洞裏我對你說的 還記得嗎?
I told you that night on the rocks,remember?
它永遠不會離開我的手指
That it would never leave my finger.And it never has.
- 為什麼? - 你知道為什麼
- Why? - You know why.
如果你曾經愛過我
If you ever loved me,
不要- - 不要奪走我的恨
don't...don't rob me of my hate.
那是我僅有的了
It's all I have.
算了吧 愛德蒙 算了
Let it go,Edmond.Let it go.
我不知道你的心裏 裝著怎樣一個惡毒的計劃
I don't know what dark plan lies within you.
我也不知道這十六年來
Nor do I know by what design we were asked...
沒有彼此的日子意味著什麼
to live without each other these 16 years.
- 但老天總算賜予了我們新的開始 - 天哪?
- But God has offered us a new beginning... - God?
不要企圖逃脫
Don't slap His hand away.
難道我永遠擺脫不了他?
Can I never escape Him?
是 他存在一切之中
No.He is in everything.
甚至在吻裏
Even in a kiss.
夫人?
My lady?
伯爵在哪裏?
Where's the count?
伯爵要你今天下午跟他在一起
Um,the count would like for you to join him this afternoon.
- 跟他在一起? - 是的
- Join him? - Uh,yes,
把這個地方留給你兒子
in,uh,leaving the country with your son.
我會叫人送你回家...
Mmm,uh,I'll have someone bring you to your house...
你就在那裏等我
and you just wait there for me.
- 我們就- - - 謝謝你
- And we just... - Thank you!
- 好 好 但- - - 我要回家收拾行李
- Yes,yes,but... - I need to go home and pack.
是的 夫人- -
Yes,yes.My lady...
- 伯爵呢? - 樓上 夫人
- Where's the count? - Upstairs,my lady.
出了什麼事?
What's wrong?
我破產了 背了所有的債
I'm bankrupt.All my debts have been called in.
- 我也會被拘捕 - 為什麼?
- Also,I'm to be arrested. - For what?
搶劫 貪污 謀殺
Piracy,corruption and murder.
- 你都干了 ? - 是的
- Did you do all these things? - Yes.
沒有時間談了 憲兵正在路上
There is simply not time to talk.The gendarmes are on the way,
快點 收拾東西
apparently,so hurry up and pack something.
我不會跟你走 費爾南多
I'm not going with you,Fernand.
你是我妻子
You are my wife.
我已經為我們安排好了
I have made arrangements for us.
我們會被照顧的很好
We shall be very well taken care of.
現在去找我的兒子
Now go and find my son.
- 他不是你的兒子 - 你說什麼
- He's not your son. - I beg your pardon?
阿爾貝 蒙德哥 是愛德蒙·唐太斯的兒子
Albert Mondego is the son of Edmond Dantes.
你想想為什麼愛德蒙·唐太斯被帶走之後
Why do you think I rushed off so quickly to marry you
我這麼匆忙地就嫁給你了?
after Edmond was taken away?
早產兒
Premature.
是的 跟你一點關係也沒有
Well,aren't you a piece of work.
他是死囚的雜種
So he's the bastard son of a dead traitor.
他總是讓人很失望
He always was disappointing.
再見 美塞苔絲 你讓我度過了一段快樂的時光
Good-bye,Mercedes.You did please me some of the time.
你從來沒有讓我快樂過
You never pleased me.
這是什麼?
What is this?
基督山
Monte Cristo.
你被控制了 費爾南多
King's to you,Fernand.
愛德蒙?
Edmond?
但怎麼- -
But how...
我怎麼逃脫的?充滿了艱辛
How did I escape?With difficulty.
我是怎樣計劃這一刻的?充滿了快樂
How did I plan this moment?With pleasure.
所以你奪走了美塞苔絲?
So you've taken Mercedes?
其他的一切...
And everything else...
除了你的生命
except your life.
為什麼要這樣做
Why are you doing this?
太複雜了
It's complicated.
我想說所有的仇恨 緣於你奪走了我的一切
Let's just say it's vengeance for the life you stole from me.
我明白了 有人教了你劍法
Well,I see someone has taught you the sword.
曾經你怎樣稱你是我的朋友?
How did you ever call yourself my friend?
- 我們是朋友 愛德蒙
We were friends,Edmond.
你讓我受盡了折磨
You sent me to hell!
為什麼?
Why?
收起你的仇恨
Take your vengeance.
你以為你流出的血是高貴的
But know the blood you spill is noble.
高貴的血永遠不會流進你的血管
Blood that will never run through your veins.
你跟平民沒什麼兩樣
You're no more a count than I am a commoner!
你的體內不會有這種血
You don't have it in you.
- 碰他 我就殺了你 - 孩子 聽我解釋
- Touch him,and I'll kill you. - Boy,let me explain.
已經解釋過了 我在街上跟維爾福夫人談過了
It's been explained.I spoke to Madame Villefort on the street.
她說我有多麼的蠢 輕易地被朋友給愚弄了
She told me how I was a silly,trusting dupe that my friend,
基督山伯爵曾經闖入過我們的生活
the Count of Monte Cristo,used to get into our lives.
- 阿爾貝 聽我說 - 我不聽
- Albert,listen to me. - I will not!
原諒我這麼傻 父親
Forgive me for being such a fool,Father.
我們都被騙了 當然不怪你
You were betrayed.Of course you're forgiven.
你是我的朋友 我尊敬你
You were my friend.I looked up to you.
有一段你不知道的歷史
There's a history here you know nothing about.
他愛你母親 然而她選擇了我
He loved your mother,and yet she chose me.
- 現在他企圖把她帶走 - 撒謊 讓開
- Now he intends to steal her away. - Lie.Get out of my way!
孩子 如果我想這樣 我會殺了你
Boy,if I have to,I will kill you.
現在我停手
I will not stop now.
- 我不會 - 休怪我無情
- Nor will I. - So be it.
不
No!
阿爾貝
Albert,
我發現了留下你去哪裏的紙條
I found the note you left explaining where you'd gone.
但現在我必須向你解釋一些事情
But now I must explain something to you.
你的真是身份
Where you really come from.
阿爾貝 你是愛德蒙唐太斯的兒子
Albert,you are the son of Edmond Dantes.
你認識的叫基督山伯爵的那個人
The man you know as the Count of Monte Cristo.
恐怕這是真的
Well,I'm afraid it is true.
你會發現你的媽媽跟妓女一樣淫蕩.
You are the walking proof that your mother was as much of a whore...
在她年輕的時候 就像今天一樣
in her younger years as she is today.
你- -
You...
你讓我跟他對抗?
You let me fight him?
不好嗎?
It didn't do any good though,did it?
費爾南多 求你 別說了
Fernand,I beg you.No more!
我不想這樣了
I want no more of this.
走吧 寬容一點
Just go.Call it mercy.
寬容 費爾南多
Mercy,Fernand.
只要你開槍 我就不會放過你
You've only got one shot,and it will take more than that to stop me.
好 那麼我最好殺了你
Well,then I'd best put it where it will do the most damage.
不
No!
媽媽
Mother!Mother!
天哪 天哪 看我做了什麼 雅格布!
Oh,my God.Oh,my God.Look what I've done.Jacopo!
駕!
Hyah!
再來一次扎特爾
Once again,Zatarra,
上帝會保佑你的
God sees you out of the corner of His eye.
她不會死
She'll live.
愛德蒙!
Edmond!
不要出去 不要
Please don't go out there.Don't.
愛德蒙 不要走
Edmond,don't go.
去 不能退縮
You try.Don't ever quit.
扎特爾
Zatarra,
你必須有個瞭解
you must end this.
牧師會明白的
Even the priest will understand that.
不要離開我
- Edmond! - Please don't leave.
照顧你母親
Watch over your mother.
現在我們不能用一句話表達你有什麼 我沒有什麼
Now,I couldn't live in a world where you have everything and I have nothing.
你的寬容呢?
What happened to your mercy?
我是伯爵 不是聖人
I'm a count,not a saint.
你是對的 牧師 你是對的
You were right,priest.You were right.
我向你發誓...
This I promise you...
還有上帝:
and God:
所有用來報仇的...
All that was used for vengeance...
將會用於善事
will now be used for good.
安息吧 我的朋友
So rest in peace,my friend.
扎特爾
So,Zatarra,
痛苦嗎?
painful,huh?
不
No.
我買了這個地方 考慮了一天還是放棄了
I bought this place,thinking one day I would tear it down.
現在我想做的唯一的事情...
But now the only things I care about...
跟我一起在島上散步
are walking off this island with me.
我們回家
Let's go home.